<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Marshall Mallicoat - misc</title><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://marshallmallicoat.com/</id><updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Vanitas</title><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/vanitas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Marshall Mallicoat</name></author><id>tag:marshallmallicoat.com,2015-07-15:/vanitas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="grave-plots"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grave Plots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents came into a couple grave plots. (I don't know how.) They're
trying to flip them, since they already have spots reserved. They say
that the cemetery in question isn't as desirable as it used to be, so
they want to unload them fast. Especially since cremation …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="grave-plots"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grave Plots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents came into a couple grave plots. (I don't know how.) They're
trying to flip them, since they already have spots reserved. They say
that the cemetery in question isn't as desirable as it used to be, so
they want to unload them fast. Especially since cremation is getting
more popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom on cremation: &lt;em&gt;You don't amount to much.&lt;/em&gt; Just a two-pint Ziploc.
She dumped her mother's ashes illegally off the Pacific coast, by where
the &lt;cite&gt;Twilight&lt;/cite&gt; movies were shot. The remainder was pressed into a bead
that she keeps on her Pandora bracelet. (This one aside, she has about
$1300 in charms on it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="notice"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've come to understand the things I've left at my parents' house, since
moving out, as &lt;em&gt;horcruxes.&lt;/em&gt; I'll keep them there safe—my old t-shirts
and books—in case I'm cut down in the street. (Tho if I was hit by a
car tomorrow, this and everything else on my computer would be lost
forever.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month I had to delete the first dead person from my email contacts:
an old boss, aged 66, a Marlboro man. Put into the bin and then the bin
emptied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a Google Alert when my grandfather's Obits4Life page went
live, since I was listed among the bereft. My inheritance remains
obscure. It's like I was left a set of shoe trees, but threw them out,
not knowing what they were for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="old-man-mallicoat"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Old Man Mallicoat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to bald gracefully. I'll keep it real short and see if I can
slide by for a couple decades. If it gets too bad, I'll shave it all off
and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eye doctor says that, if I keep using computers, my eyes will slowly
get worse and worse forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dentist says that I grind my teeth in my sleep, probably due to
stress. So now I go to sleep in shorts and a mouthguard like a boxer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a weekend in the city, I'll have black snot and my fingers will be
swollen red around the nail. I feel like my body is already rotting.
Like I'm being fitted for the big &amp;amp; tall in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my wake, lay me out on a California king. Run my obituary in the
&lt;cite&gt;Kansas City Star&lt;/cite&gt;, my preferred newspaper of record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vanity"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vanity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desk dictionary memorializes Christopher Columbus as thus: &lt;em&gt;1451-1506
Ital. navigator; disc. Am.&lt;/em&gt; I doubt my legacy will be abbreviated so
succinctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They think Los Angeles will been underwater in 100 years. I estimate
I've eaten 4800 peanut butter sandwiches in my lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bell peppers change color from green to yellow or orange and then to
red. I suspect this is the original metaphor for traffic lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implicit in everything I write here is the assumption that the world has
never ended. Now that it’s been said, I don’t know why that seemed like
such a statement to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>John Henry</title><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/john-henry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Marshall Mallicoat</name></author><id>tag:marshallmallicoat.com,2015-06-21:/john-henry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="emails-from-your-boss-written-in-the-form-of-a-question-with-a-period-at-the-end"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Emails from your boss, written in the form of a question, with a period at the end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart people are house slaves to the rich. Even among the aliens, the
Nordic whites rule over the little greens and grays. To my landlord, I
am an encumbrance on the property. To …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="emails-from-your-boss-written-in-the-form-of-a-question-with-a-period-at-the-end"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Emails from your boss, written in the form of a question, with a period at the end&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart people are house slaves to the rich. Even among the aliens, the
Nordic whites rule over the little greens and grays. To my landlord, I
am an encumbrance on the property. To my employer, a capital outlay. I
find it hard to believe that, in three million years of fossil record,
there is not a single lizard man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some open questions: Why does the cable company need my Social Security
number? Why does my boss need to know my credit score? How come I can't
give &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; a piss test? Where do cows get their calcium, if they only
eat grass? And their protein, for that matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spy satellites are so high up, they always look straight down. If you
face forward, they can only see the top of your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a spot behind the security desk at the mall where I can watch
the guards idly browse the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="john-henry"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;John Henry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To survive in white collar labor, you must cultivate a certain
lassitude, and wear it as a suit of armor. If the work load is heavy,
you have to drag your feet, since even if you finish early you won't get
sent home. If the work load is light, you have to pretend to be working
hard or you will get assigned more work. In any case, you must also
appear to be having a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the railroads were built, work songs were sung to set the pace of
labor. It kept everyone working at a level of exertion that could be
kept up all day in the hot sun without risking death. It also kept every
working at the same rate, so no one could foolishly work harder to win
the graces of the foreman—which would force everyone else to work
harder, and thereby endanger both their welfare and their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the office, there's no sound other than the dull hum of the air
conditioner and the cricketsong of computers. And your coworkers are all
blood doping—cranking on the commute, then drinking themselves to
sleep at night. How can you keep up without joining in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Henry was able to beat the steel-driving machine through sheer effort.
But afterward, his heart gave out and he soon died. The &amp;quot;Ballad of John
Henry&amp;quot; says “That old hammer killed John Henry / but that old hammer
won't kill me”. I'm saying, that old hammer won't kill me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="not-an-apartment-but-a-dark-hole-i-lived-in-for-3-years"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not an apartment, but a dark hole I lived in for 3 years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To vacate an apartment without incident feels like getting away with a
crime. You drag your mattress down the stairwell and leave it in a
dumpster like a warm body. Having recouped the full deposit, you skip
town before the landlord gets wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To live is to be in constant fear of legal retribution: speeding,
jaywalking, illegal downloading, cheating on your taxes, and so on. The
state of Connecticut defines “loitering” as: standing around, moving
slowly about, spending time idly, sauntering, dallying, lingering, or
lagging behind. In Florida, twenty grams is a felony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you found a pair of crystal antlers. How could you explain having a
pair of crystal antlers to the police? Better to play it safe and
quickly dispose of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you hear sirens, you think it's for you. When you see a cop,
you think &amp;quot;so this is how it ends&amp;quot;. It's only a matter of time before
the black helicopters swoop down to snatch you up. As for me, I know my
last days will be described as &lt;em&gt;brazen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Junkie, don't talk to me</title><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/junkie.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Marshall Mallicoat</name></author><id>tag:marshallmallicoat.com,2015-05-09:/junkie.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="cold-water-after-black-coffee-is-like-tempering-steel"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cold water after black coffee is like tempering steel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've come to a calm in the midst of my mid-morning coffee—my first and
only coffee of the day. The fog in my head burns off. The wool-legged
spiders who cobweb my attic disperse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caffeine doesn't bring euphoria—more like …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="cold-water-after-black-coffee-is-like-tempering-steel"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cold water after black coffee is like tempering steel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've come to a calm in the midst of my mid-morning coffee—my first and
only coffee of the day. The fog in my head burns off. The wool-legged
spiders who cobweb my attic disperse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caffeine doesn't bring euphoria—more like an elasticity to your limbs
and a humming in your head, from the amplified sound of your blood. And
a feeling like being wrapped in warm, clean towels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's only good for the first few sips. Just as you start to enjoy
the high, you've already peaked. By the time you finish, you're past the
plateau and down in the valley after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I'm only happy for 15 minutes at a time, followed by a
headache. And with it comes boredom. Not a boredom like watching paint
dry, but watching paint that had recently dried. The grass growing in
the lawn has stalled out, and I'm languishing in a terminal middle-class
lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="taking-dexedrine-at-2am-in-nyc-to-hold-you-through-till-5am-when-grand-central-re-opens-and-you-can-get-a-train-back-to-connecticut"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking Dexedrine at 2am in NYC to hold you through till 5am when Grand Central re-opens and you can get a train back to Connecticut&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd say, if caffeine was a taxi conducting your body through the human
traffic, that Dexedrine is a black sedan speeding through a tunnel at
night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="junkie"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Junkie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can tell when my mom has been drinking coffee. She is jubilant. She is
effervescent. She &lt;em&gt;bubbles&lt;/em&gt;. I tell her, &amp;quot;Don't talk to me, junkie.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She started drinking coffee because she was narcoleptic and would fall
asleep while driving. I only started drinking coffee after I started
taking caffeine pills. Which I only took with alcohol, to make drinking
less miserable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read an insightful observation somewhere, maybe in a Gawker comment,
that Lindsay Lohan wasn't a cokehead, just an alcoholic who took cocaine
to be able to drink more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coffee-as-ideology"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coffee as ideology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You're in the city and there's coffee to buy. Either with brunch or
after when you walk around the shops. Later there's beer. Someone's
in town for a few days or it's a going away party. You drink and talk
and make plans to meet at the new brunch place in the morning. They
have the best espresso.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pass code for the bathroom at the Union Square Starbucks on July
4, 2014, was 8282. And I gave it away to the first person I saw: a
Russian tourist standing in line. In turn, she gave it to the people
behind her. In this way, she was my first apostle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I prefer the discretion of pill poppers and day drunks to the
perverts who go to cafes after dark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hairy-man"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hairy Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the March 2014 issue of &lt;cite&gt;The Red Bulletin&lt;/cite&gt;, an interview with Nicolas
Cage (“Being Nicolas Cage”) opens with “Do you think about death?” (He
does.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the grocery store by the energy drinks, there is a sign that says
&amp;quot;This area is monitored by Closed Circuit Television.&amp;quot; In the aisle by
the safety razors, the same sign, plus a sliding plastic shield across
the shelf—presumably to slow you down when scooping them into your
trash bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implication is that there exists a cohort of congenitally hairy men
(or one Hairy Man) who both fiends for caffeine and is willing to do
anything to alleviate his condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on sports</title><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/thoughts-on-sports.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2015-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Marshall Mallicoat</name></author><id>tag:marshallmallicoat.com,2015-03-02:/thoughts-on-sports.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="golf"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Golf&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inner workings of a miniature golf course amount to a secret gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miniature golf is to golf what reality TV is to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In golf, you swing lowercase L's at the tops of semicolons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bowling alley, they give you golf pencils to keep score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandfather …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="golf"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Golf&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inner workings of a miniature golf course amount to a secret gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miniature golf is to golf what reality TV is to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In golf, you swing lowercase L's at the tops of semicolons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bowling alley, they give you golf pencils to keep score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandfather owned both a set of clubs and a bowling ball. My father
has neither.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've invented a new drink that's half-Arnold Palmer and half-Shirley
Temple, called the LBJ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guessing a woman's age is a kind of golf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-sports"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Sports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baseball is basically unwatchable, but it works on the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The counter-insurgency is Whac-a-Mole, the drug war Three-card Monte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalism has wrought the moneyballing of everything. The Dutch work 6
hours a day, then ride bikes home. Americans work for 6 hours, spend 2
hours on Facebook, then crawl through traffic for 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who sits very still at a desk all day, looking at small numbers
on a screen, is a kind of athlete. It takes endurance. You need training
and preparation to do it without hurting yourself. These are grown men
with all the hair rubbed off their ankles by socks, and prostates the
size of clenched fists. They will show you their game face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highest compliment you can pay a man is to call him a machine. Men
strive to make themselves into weapons. This is done through emotional
distance, rituals of control, and repetition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="on-sportsmanship"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On Sportsmanship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a high school wrestler for one day. I was on the swimming team but
quit. After failing to induce vomiting in the bathroom, I lied about
having vomited to get out of practice. At a strip mall dojo, I put my
fist through the drywall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In job interviews, I extemporize on my temperament as if I were a race
horse. As long as they let me down easy, I don't care if I don't get a
call back. To be listed among the also-rans is enough for me. I'm like a
retired greyhound who's too skinny to lie down on hardwood floors. I
understand back pain—what I lack is &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt; for my back pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a picture of the man with the biggest hands in the world, posing
with a basketball. But he doesn't even play basketball. He just holds it
for photographs. It's like that guy who says he's crazy about football,
only he never watches the games, doesn't know the rules, it just pops
into his mind every once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>In the twilight of GMT+1</title><link href="https://marshallmallicoat.com/in-the-twilight.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2015-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Marshall Mallicoat</name></author><id>tag:marshallmallicoat.com,2015-02-02:/in-the-twilight.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The telegraph was an early internet, with its own lolcats and leetspeak.
To people in the future, we probably seem like steampunks: one foot in the
last century, carrying our brains around in our pockets like
Tamagotchis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open a file on your computer, you touch an arrowhead to a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The telegraph was an early internet, with its own lolcats and leetspeak.
To people in the future, we probably seem like steampunks: one foot in the
last century, carrying our brains around in our pockets like
Tamagotchis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open a file on your computer, you touch an arrowhead to a tiny
picture of a manila folder. When you want to save, an artist's rendering
of a 3.5” floppy disk. Clicking on a trashcan will de-index a block of
memory. If the world was Tetris, we'd all have roofs with holes in them
(or no roofs at all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buddhist prayers wheels have a mantra written around so that, when spun,
it is like the mantra is being read. The Dalai Lama has said that having
the mantra on your computer works the same as a traditional wheel. As
the digital image spins on your hard drive, it sends the peaceful prayer
of compassion in all directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Malaysian space agency recommends that Muslim astronauts, if they
cannot determine the direction of Mecca, pray in the direction of the
Earth. Failing that, any direction is acceptable. Additionally they
advise you to &amp;quot;observe peace with other beings.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Tibet and Nepal, they still practice sky burials, where bodies are
stripped and laid out for the vultures to eat. But the bodies that have
been given medicine or cleaned in hospitals make the vultures sick, so
they have to be buried in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the most coveted donors for knee replacements are Muslim men.
Their patella are kept flexible by the years of praying on their knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have never been middle-aged rappers before. And you can't even
make a rapper admit to rapping anymore. They've become demure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when pay phones cost 35 cents. I remember pay phones. I asked
around and confirmed that they don't even play beer pong with beer in
the cups anymore. They just keep score on paper. We will be among the
last people on Earth to remember before the Internet, if yet we still
do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>